{
    "id": "3535e72af8084b3ba53e062c0bfaf35d",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "At no time …………………………. her self control.",
            "description": "When a negative word comes at the beginning we use an inverted word order.",
            "answers": [
                "did she lose",
                "she lost",
                "did she lost"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I hadn’t seen her ………………………….. years, but she wasn’t any different.",
            "description": "We use for to indicate duration.",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "This job is different from …………………………… I expected.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Have you got …………………………. more coffee?",
            "description": "In questions we use any. ",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "some",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Today is …………………………… than yesterday.",
            "description": "We cannot use very to modify comparative adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "very colder",
                "much colder",
                "very much colder"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t tell you …………………………….. pleased I am about the result.",
            "description": "We can use ‘how’ to express the idea of ‘how much’.",
            "answers": [
                "how",
                "what",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Is this the first time you …………………………… here?",
            "description": "We use the present perfect tense with ‘this is the first time’ etc.",
            "answers": [
                "stayed",
                "have stayed",
                "had stayed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The car was damaged ……………………… a falling branch.",
            "description": "In passive clauses we use by to introduce the agent.",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "by",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I have always ………………………… to play games well.",
            "description": "We cannot use ‘can’ with have. Instead, we use be able to.",
            "answers": [
                "been able",
                "could",
                "able"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I lost my job ………………………….. I was ill for six months.",
            "description": "We use because to introduce the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "as",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The storm blew their roof ………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "off",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I …………………………… law.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would study",
                "would have studied",
                "will have studied"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}